Leena Lallmon

Montreal, Canada 💹 leena.lallmon@gmail.com in leenalallmon 🤘 leenalallmon.com

Summary

I'm a Software Engineer based in Montreal, Canada who enjoys problem solving. I am the co-creator of Fjord (fjord-framework.github.io 2), an open source framework that provides a real-time API Proxy for Apache Kafka. I have multiple years of experience in the Ruby and JavaScript ecosystems, and I am comfortable with Golang, AWS and Docker.

Professional Experience

Co-creator & Software Engineer, *Fjord*

2021 - present

- Utilizes languages and technologies such as JavaScript, AWS ECS, AWS Fargate, AWS Elasticache for Redis, Docker and Server-Sent Events
- Collaborated on the prototype of the API Server and Kafka Consumer process using Node.js, KafkaJS and MongoDB
- Isolated and containerized Fjord components using Docker for deployment to AWS cloud infrastructure
- Implemented distributed Kafka system to test Fjord
- Load tested to handle over 8500 concurrent connections
- Utilized a CLI tool that deploys all of Fjord's AWS components based on user's requirements
- Co-authored a comprehensive technical case study

 documenting design decisions

Full-Stack Web Developer, Self-Employed

2020 - 2021

Developed open-source software, some highlighted projects include:

- Ruby Blogger, a Ruby library command line developer tool to track exceptions
- Contact Manager, a JavaScript, Express, Bulma CRUD app with a Node
- Spry, a Kanban style Trello clone built with MongoDB, Express, React, Redux and axios

Social Worker, Various Employers

2011 - 2019

- Work in food security, mental health and austism
- Founding member of ADAMA (Association de développement des arts martiaux adaptés)

Skills

Backend

- Node.is
- Express
- Ruby
- SQL
- RESTful APIs
- Webhooks
- SSE

Frontend

- JavaScript (ES6)
- React
- Redux
- HTML
- EventSource API

Tooling Git

- Github
- Docker
- Linux

Cloud

- AWS EC2
- AWS ECS
- AWS Fargate
- AWS Elasticache for Redis
- AWS VPC
- AWS ALB
- GCP VM
- Digital Ocean Droplet

Education

Software Engineering & Full Stack Development, Education ☑

2020 - 2021